{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Surface plate is used to check the trueness of flat surfaces.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A zinc diffusion process is called", "opta": "galvanising", "optb": "anodising", "optc": "parkerising", "optd": "sherardizing", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The accuracy of micrometers, calipers, dial indicators can be checked by a", "opta": "feeler gauge", "optb": "slip gauge", "optc": "ring gauge", "optd": "plug gauge", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The type of file used for a wood work is", "opta": "single-cut file", "optb": "double cut file", "optc": "rasp-cut file", "optd": "any one of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A taper provided on the pattern for its easy and clean withdrawl from the mould is known as", "opta": "machining allowance", "optb": "draft allowance", "optc": "shrinkage allowance", "optd": "distortion allowance", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In arc welding, the electric arc is produced between the work and the electrode by", "opta": "voltage", "optb": "flow of current", "optc": "contact resistance", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a centrifugal casting method", "opta": "core is made of sand", "optb": "core is made of ferrous metal", "optc": "core is made of non-ferrous metal", "optd": "no core is used", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The draft or taper allowance on casting is generally", "opta": "1 to 2 mm/m", "optb": "2 to 5 mm/m", "optc": "5 to 10 mm/m", "optd": "10 to 15 mm/m", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following welding process uses non-consumable electrodes?", "opta": "TIG welding", "optb": "MIG welding", "optc": "Manual arc welding", "optd": "Submerged arc welding", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a bilateral system of tolerance, the tolerance is allowed on", "opta": "one side of the actual size", "optb": "one side of the nominal size", "optc": "both sides of the actual size", "optd": "both sides of the nominal size", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a hot chamber die casting machine", "opta": "ferrous alloys with low melting temperature are casted", "optb": "ferrous alloys with high melting temperature are casted", "optc": "non-ferrous alloys with low melting temperature are casted", "optd": "non-ferrous alloys with high melting temperature are casted", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The chisel used for cutting key ways is", "opta": "flat chisel", "optb": "cape chisel", "optc": "round nose chisel", "optd": "diamond pointed chisel", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The temperature at which the new grains are formed in the metal is called", "opta": "lower critical temperature", "optb": "upper critical temperature", "optc": "eutectic temperature", "optd": "recrystallisation temperature", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Thread rolling is restricted to", "opta": "ferrous materials", "optb": "ductile materials", "optc": "hard materials", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In sheet metal blanking, shear is provided on punches and dies so that", "opta": "press load is reduced", "optb": "good cut edge is obtained", "optc": "warping of sheet is minimised", "optd": "cut blanks are straight", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In welding copper alloys with TIG arc welding", "opta": "direct current with straight polarity is used", "optb": "direct current with reversed polarity is used", "optc": "alternating current is used", "optd": "any one of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The algebraic difference between the minimum limit and the basic size is called", "opta": "actual deviation", "optb": "upper deviation", "optc": "lower deviation", "optd": "fundamental deviation", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The temperature of oxy-hydrogen flame is __________ oxy-acetylene flame.", "opta": "same as", "optb": "less than", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following methods can be used for manufacturing 2 metre long seamless metallic tubes?", "opta": "Drawing", "optb": "Extrusion", "optc": "Rolling", "optd": "Extrusion and rolling", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A saw which cuts wood during the return stroke of the saw is known as", "opta": "push saw", "optb": "pull saw or draw saw", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The low pressure acetylene is produced at the welding site by the chemical reaction between water and calcium carbonate.", "opta": "Correct", "optb": "Incorrect", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The fullers are used", "opta": "for finishing flat surfaces", "optb": "for necking down a piece of work", "optc": "for punching a hole", "optd": "to finish the punched hole", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cold chisels are made by", "opta": "drawing", "optb": "rolling", "optc": "piercing", "optd": "forging", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The property of sand due to which it evolves a great amount of steam and other gases is called", "opta": "collapsibility", "optb": "permeability", "optc": "cohesiveness", "optd": "adhesiveness", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The centrifugal casting method, is used for casting articles of", "opta": "symmetrical shape about vertical axis", "optb": "symmetrical shape about horizontal axis", "optc": "irregular shape", "optd": "non-ferrous metal only", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Metal patterns are used for", "opta": "small castings", "optb": "large castings", "optc": "complicated castings", "optd": "large scale production of castings", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The instrument which has all the features of try-square, bevel protractor, rule and scriber, is", "opta": "outside micrometer", "optb": "inside micrometer", "optc": "depth gauge micrometer", "optd": "combination set", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a hole or cavity to be cored is not in line with the parting surface, then a __________ is used.", "opta": "horizontal core", "optb": "vertical core", "optc": "drop core", "optd": "balanced core", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bloom is smaller than a billet.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In average work, the tolerance produced by investment casting method is", "opta": "\u00b10.05 mm", "optb": "+0.2 mm", "optc": "+05 mm", "optd": "+1 mm", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The purpose of a riser is to", "opta": "deliver molten metal into the mould cavity", "optb": "act as a reservoir for the molten metal", "optc": "feed the molten metal to the casting in order to compensate for the shrinkage", "optd": "deliver the molten metal from pouring basin to gate", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The blank diameter used in thread rolling will be", "opta": "equal to minor diameter of the thread", "optb": "equal to pitch diameter of the thread", "optc": "a little larger than the minor diameter of the thread", "optd": "a little larger than the pitch diameter of the thread", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cross-section of a chisel is usually", "opta": "rectangular", "optb": "square", "optc": "hexagonal", "optd": "octagonal", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A plug gauge is used to check the diameter of shafts and studs.", "opta": "Correct", "optb": "Incorrect", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In back-hand welding, the angle between the welding torch and the work is kept as", "opta": "30\u00b0-40\u00b0", "optb": "40\u00b0-50\u00b0", "optc": "50\u00b0-60\u00b0", "optd": "60\u00b0-70\u00b0", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The machining allowance provided on patterns depends upon", "opta": "type of casting metal", "optb": "size and shape of casting", "optc": "method of casting used", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In submerged arc welding, an arc is produced between a", "opta": "carbon electrode and the work", "optb": "metal electrode and the work", "optc": "bare metal electrode and the work", "optd": "two tungsten electrodes and the work", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In shielded arc welding", "opta": "large electrode is used", "optb": "welding rod coated with slag is used", "optc": "welding rod coated with fluxing material is used", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a die casting method, the molten metal is forced into mould under high pressure.", "opta": "Correct", "optb": "Incorrect", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a centrifugal casting method, the impurities are collected in the centre of the casting.", "opta": "Yes", "optb": "No", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a hot chamber die casting machine", "opta": "melting pot is separate from the machine", "optb": "melting pot is an integral part of the machine", "optc": "melting pot may have any location", "optd": "high temperature and pressure is used", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The electrodes used in spot welding have a tip of", "opta": "stainless steel", "optb": "aluminium", "optc": "copper", "optd": "brass", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Blanking and piercing operations can be performed simultaneously in a", "opta": "simple die", "optb": "progressive die", "optc": "compound die", "optd": "combination die", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A pattern maker's shrinkage rule considers", "opta": "all pattern allowances", "optb": "only shrinkage allowance", "optc": "all materials to be cast", "optd": "all materials of the pattern", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The tolerance produced by shell moulding process of casting is", "opta": "+0.05 mm", "optb": "\u00b10.2 mm", "optc": "+0.5 mm", "optd": "\u00b11 mm", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Galvanising is a", "opta": "zinc diffusion process", "optb": "process of coating zinc by hot dipping", "optc": "process used for making thin phosphate coating on steel", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ferrous metals require more machining allowance than non-ferrous metals.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a four high rolling mill, there are four rolls out of which", "opta": "one is working roll and three are backing up rolls", "optb": "two are working rolls and two are backing up rolls", "optc": "three are working rolls and one is backing up roll", "optd": "all of the four are working rolls", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a pattern is made in three parts, the bottom part is known as a cope.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In __________ welding, the weld may be made either from left to right or from right to left.", "opta": "fore-hand", "optb": "back-hand", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}